hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
talk about ways for you to grow in your
life and in your business as a coach
course creator Mentor trainer somebody
who wants to make six seven and even
eight figures like our clients have
selling digital courses or coaching
online we're one of the best resources
that exists on the internet and this
podcast is one of the best free
resources that
exists we are over 240 plus gosh I don't
even know what the number is on this
episode but uh we have a lot of episodes
and they're all made for you if you want
to make 100,000 200,000 500,000 a
million dollar like I have like my
clients have in a coaching course
digital product you want to write a
non-fiction book you want to pass on
information to people and you want to
build a brand to become an authority in
your industry in your
Niche this is the podcast for you and
this episode is going to take you from
just having a spark of an
idea to actually possibly taking action
for the first time in your
life so sit back
enjoy and let's dive into the podcast
I'm excited today so the format that
this podcast Works a little bit
different than other podcast it's
literally basically just me rambling on
camera for about 20 to 30 minutes um but
it's thoughts that either I'm still
processing have processed have taught
but I know that are impactful that I
need to make out in the open for people
and one of the number one things that I
realized that I tapped into this week is
that most
people uh don't put themselves out there
with a course or coaching business
because they don't know what's going to
happen and that can be the worst
possible
thing they don't want to disappoint
people they don't want to upset people
they don't want to waste time they don't
want to lose money they don't want to
lose energy they don't want they don't
want things to work out how they want
them to okay we've we've talked about
that in like dozens of podcast episodes
in the
past but I realized this past week I I
haven't talked about something until
just this
week with a number of like couple
hundred people I've shared this with and
they were all like oh my God this blew
my mind and so that's what I'm going to
that's what I'm going to share with you
is what that
is
is you have to take an iterative
experimentation what I call an alpha
release approach
to your course or coaching business okay
we can use chat GPT incredible resource
AI is changing the game to be able to
dial in we going to be drinking sewage
water this is what H whoops clicked the
link on my phone and then something
pulled up about sewage water
anyways that's
funny we could spend all this time work
with AI to dial in our topic and our
modules and come up with it the problem
that I see that happens with people is
they sit there and they make it better
and better and improve it and improve it
on
paper but they don't actually put it out
there to
people they don't actually put it out
there in front of the public to be
scrutinized
judged and I
know it's gosh it's that's uncomfortable
that's why it
stinks it hurts people are mean that are
out there and so if we can just do
everything perfect and it's excellent at
the moment we put it out there then we
lower the risk of the
negativity the problem with that
is for most people and I've worked with
thousands of course creators and coaches
on
this their course or their coaching
program never at the level that they
feel like it's good enough to put out
there that there's always more that they
could do to improve it to make it better
before they actually put it out
there they never make
money they never impact
people because their
perfectionism keeps it
inside they don't share their gift with
others a gift is something that you give
away to other
people not something that you hold into
yourself I would be doing a disservice
and not following my calling to not
record this podcast to not coach people
to not sell my coaching to not generate
millions of dollars in
business and yet there are people to
this day that think that I am wrong for
doing all of
that they s send me emails breaking down
why the 10 tenants as to how horrible I
am of a
person and what I do is I just throw it
in the trash and ignore it and I
literally ignore their opinions and some
of you might be saying well gosh isn't
that rude no it's not often times we
want other people to take our opinions
so much that we take in all the trash
that people trying to dump on us well in
fact it's better just ignore
it put yourself out there and not care
what anybody thinks about it
period even if people don't like it even
if they're disappointed even if they say
you could have done
better but most people won't do
that because their
need to make everything
perfect is greater than their actual
desire to be
successful and to impact people and to
make the kind of money that they could
possibly make their need to be right and
to quote unquote do it right is more
important than actually doing anything
at
all and that's just uh I I I've gotten
to the point now I you know and I might
I might lose some subscribers and
followers you may turn off the podcast
after what I'm about to
say I no long longer have tolerance for
lazy people like
that at
all people who are all talk all dream
never do anything oh yeah we're going to
do it we're going to go ahead we're
going to start to do that yeah and then
a year later nothing and then New Year's
rolls around they like oh yeah we're
going to do it we're going to do it in
the new year and then nothing ever
happens and then they come up with their
list of why they were doing 50 other
things that were more
important sure
and I know that that might sound
harsh but that's why this is on this
podcast that's
why you know I think you should share
this episode with some people that might
need a little bit of a swift kick in the
pants to realize that maybe that's been
their pattern maybe that's been their
behavior maybe that's been what they've
been doing and they have a dream and
they have a calling and they know where
they're supposed to go and yet they're
sitting around waiting for the clouds to
apart for them to quote unquote feel
peace in their heart about it instead of
just doing something you know when it
comes to actually doing something you're
often not going to feel peace about it
when you're about to do it the peace
actually usually comes later by doing it
scared and choosing to sit on your butt
and do nothing is a
choice it's not a passive
activity and some people say well I'm
not doing nothing I'm doing this and
this and this and this and this and yet
they're doing everything
but putting their stuff out there to
other people well it's not ready yet
it's not
better so that's why I'm saying take an
alpha an alpha release
approach what is an alpha release an
alpha release is a term in
software an alpha
release is part of software testing and
if you're on the podcast on YouTube you
can see I'm pulling up the screen here
to explain a little bit about how an
alpha release works so an alpha release
means that the features are still
incomplete and continuous testing is
needed before it's officially released
to the public it's tested and released
to a small subset of people and this is
what coaches course graders mentors
trainers and authors need to do and
often times what this looks like is it's
it's your first book it's your first
course it's your first program it's your
first event it's your first thing it's
not
perfect but it's part of the iterative
process and I bet you can look in your
life at the last 10 15 years that you
actually do this in other areas of your
life and have been very successful
because you finally have gained the
courage to be okay with not caring what
other people think and learning to let
go of it needing to be perfect and yet
when it comes to your course business
business or you're coaching business or
you're writing a book or you're
mentoring or you're growing a
church or you're building a college or
something like that
like waiting for things to happen
waiting for situations to change instead
of being the
change is where people go and they take
a passive role a backseat role on their
calling and I really can't stand it when
people use God to justify
this well I'm just waiting on the Lord
waiting on his timing and and listen
I've been called a wolf in sheep's
clothing for what I just
said I have
had uh pastors walk me out of their
church and tell me that I have a spirit
of
antichrist for encouraging people
to not wait on the Lord and take action
and actually step up and do something
here's the thing I I truly believe this
pray like you are not responsible ask
God trust and then take action like you
are responsible and do your very best
here's the thing you know when my wife
and I we were praying for a
baby we had to do some things to make it
happen we couldn't just talk about
it not going to go into details but like
you know you know what I mean and part
of that was we I had to get my health in
order we had to take action we couldn't
just take a a backseat roll and say
we're just waiting on things to change
we prayed we trusted but we also did as
best as we could when we bought this
house when I built my business I trust
God but I also
act based around my own responsibility
all right so again I'm not getting into
a theological debate on
that you've been waiting long
enough
there is this
lie that people
believe called that says well you only
have one chance at a first impression so
you might as well set it right and I'm
sorry but that's a load of crud it
really
is because you can put something out
there and then improve it
later sure will you lose a few people of
course but who cares what like stop
trying to control everything so much our
need to control
everything is why we can't actually get
things
going the need to control things is the
fastest way to make sure that nothing
goes how you want it to or how you
dreamed or how you feel
called and I'm not just saying this
flapping my jaws about my op an opinion
this is
literally my life story story that I've
been living for the last 10
years is realizing this it's why in the
last year my business has grown to be a
million-dollar business it's
why we're impacting more people than we
ever have in our business it's why my
relationships with my family and my wife
are better than they've ever
been because I stopped taking a backseat
rooll and hoping things would change
and here's the other thing if we're
waiting until the perfect circumstances
where everything calms down where okay I
finally have room in my schedule to do
those things that's the worst time to do
it the best time to start is when you
don't have
time when you don't have a clear
schedule when it looks like everything
is against you that's actually the best
time to start why because you figure out
how to make it work in the toughest
times because that's what allows you to
sustain
it that's what allows you to build it
that's what allows you to continue it
now of course I believe in
praying Discerning listening to what God
is calling us to
do but then you got to do
something and way too many people are
just waiting for things to change in
their life waiting for situations to
change and nothing ever
changes they've been waiting on the Lord
for 10 20
years again I I get it some of y'all
might completely disagree with
this I'm not here to win a popularity
contest and I am okay with the hate
mail because I want those that are ready
to hear this to change their life I'm
not talking about burning yourself out
I'm not talking about stressing yourself
out pushing striving in
fact success happens by pulling back and
resting not striving so hard but
actually pulling back and resting and
learning to to relax and to calm your
nervous system down to calm the fight
ORF flight response to calm the trauma
response to be able to discern clearly
and to know what iic moves to make
creativity in our brains is
unlocked when we actually learn to let
go of trying to control
everything and so holding these two
ideas in your mind at the same time
letting
go and controlling what you can
control and really what I see it as is
almost like a roller coaster you're at
the top of the roller coaster you have
this break in your hand and you have to
learn to literally let it go and go down
the hill
and accept whatever happens happens and
be okay with it not being perfect be
okay with people being disappointed be
okay with people being mad at you being
okay with people judging you harshly and
even people telling you and even people
trying to stop
you I've experienced all of this I have
had people literally call me up and tell
me
Jeremiah it is my mission until the day
that I die to make sure that you never
succeed and they went out there and they
Ed everybody that we had in common and
told them lies about me to never work
with me all this kind of
stuff did I go out there and try to
defend myself and change it and control
it and all no what a waste of time if
those people are going to believe that
person I don't need to convince them I'm
focused on those that absolutely love
what we're doing they absolutely connect
with
it and that's what you want to do
sometimes shifting into the new season
means you're going to shift into a
different audience a different group of
friends a different atmosphere and it
feels different and that's why it might
feel chaotic that's why it might shake
some things up that's why it might shake
the boat up but in the end it's 100%
worth it every single
time so I want to encourage
you don't let the
fear of things not working perfectly
stop you from even taking the first step
because here's the thing I don't believe
see I see people do this I'm planning
I'm Sting the found I know a I know a
wonderful lady I'm sure she's an
incredible lady she's been planning the
foundations for her coaching business
for 10 years and hasn't put anything out
there because she's making it
perfect and I feel sorry for her because
I bet there's some trauma and things
like that she she's dealt with she's
dealt with some hard
stuff she listens to my stuff too to and
I and I understand that and I feel for
her because I know the potential of what
could be accomplished but she doesn't
see it she's so caught up in the weeds
of survival mode that she won't step
into thriving mode in her
life thriving mode happens by doing
things that we know will move the needle
forward in the trajectory when it's not
convenient for
us we have to stop waiting for things to
be convenient for
us to start moving forward
and that will unlock massive levels of
growth for
you we have to stop waiting until we
have a guaranteed how things are going
to pan
out what absolute stupidity and some
people think it's stupid to not do that
okay maybe in other Industries maybe in
other businesses stop worrying so much
what other people think about you and
trying to control their perceptions of
every single move you
make let them hate you let them dis
disown you let them misunderstand you
let them think the worst about
you and just keep doing
it and that will make you more
successful keep putting yourself out
there keep showing up eventually they'll
come by and ask how did you start doing
that how did you get
started it's about being resilient when
you take the hits to not get knocked
down to not stay down and to keep
getting up and to keep moving
forward life is not all sunshine and
rainbows and yes I just paraphrased a
line from the
movie
Rocky I understand that it's I love that
line from it because it's so
good life will beat you up beat you to a
pulp and try to convince you to
stop but it's not about avoiding the
hits It's about taking the hits and you
keep getting up and that's what winning
is you keep moving
forward I believe in
you learn to develop thick skin learn to
strengthen
your ability to do that that's why I I
talk to a therapist that's why I've
worked through the things that have
stopped me from being successful because
I know what direction that I'm going and
I know the calling that I have on my
life and I know what I can do and what
God expects of
me and for me to sit by idly when people
try to stop me and make it their mission
to destroy me and write me in nasty
letters tell me how horrible I am I had
one last week come in somebody wrote me
telling me that
they they listened to a message where I
talked about how I struggled with I
struggled with alcohol 12 years ago and
I don't drink in at all alcohol at all
anymore and this person wrote me and
said you know I can't trust you anymore
Jeremiah you went to jail can't trust a
person who's a
criminal so sorry sorry I'm not
perfect never claimed to be the only
perfect person that there ever was was
Jesus and they hung him on a
cross what I can do is help you succeed
what I can do is help you get results
stop waiting for
Perfection keep moving
forward put yourself out there even if
it
means that things aren't going to work
out perfectly the first time out even if
it means it might make you look dumb to
some people
even if it means some people might laugh
at you and tell you you're a
joke keep doing it keep showing
up and that my friends is what will make
you successful all right listen I know
this podcast has offended some
people I hope they never listen to me
again it did but I know some of y'all
really connected with this and resonated
with it and if that's if that's the case
make sure to plug into the other
episodes and pass this on and share it
with somebody share it with one person
that you know needs to hear this this
week great your life everybody we'll
talk soon have a good
[Music]
[Applause]
one